A Catalog of Instrumental Music Published Before ca. 1800 in the Alexander Mackay-Smith Collection of the University of Virginia
University of Virginia Library
- DOUZE WALTZ Et Douze Allemandes Pour deux Flûtes COMPOSÉES ET DÉDIÉES A ses Elèves PAR L.A. MARJOLIN. PRIX 4frs. 50 Cmes. A LYON, Chez l'Auteur Petite rue Mercière, No. 12, Bis. A PARIS, Chez tous les Marchands de nouveautés. Enrégistré à la Bibliothèque Impériale. Propriété de l'Editeur., Between 1804 and 1814 ("Bibliothèque Impériale"); Deest.; Imperfect copy. One part, quarto, 244x192 (280x209): FLAUTO Io.: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-9. Blank, [10]. Title-page of FLAUTO I signed: "Marjolin". Bound with nos. 101, 211, 212, and 216.
  No. 1 WALTZ D
  No. 2 ALLEMANDE D
  [no indication] 2/4
  No. 3 WALTZ G
  No. 4 ALLEMANDE G
  No. 5 WALTZ F
  No. 6 ALLEMANDE F
  No. 7 WALTZ C
  No. 8 ALLEMANDE C
  No. 9 WALTZ B♭
  No. 10 ALLEMANDE B♭
  No. 11 WALTZ b
  No. 12 ALLEMANDE b
  No. 13 WALTZ G
  No. 14 ALLEMANDE G
  No. 15 WALTZ D
  No. 16 ALLEMANDE D
  No. 17 WALTZ e
  No. 18 ALLEMANDE e
  No. 19 WALTZ F
  No. 20 ALLEMANDE F
  No. 21 WALTZ D
  No. 22 ALLEMANDE D
  No. 23 WALTZ G
  No. 24 ALLEMANDE G
  Waltzes et allemandes, flutes, (2); Marjolin, L. A.; Paris (France); Lyon (France); B♭; C; D; F; G; B; E; 2/4; 3/8; [no indication]
  - FLAUTO Io.
- SIX SONATES EN TRIO Pour deux Violons et Basse DÉDIÉES A Milord John lord VISCOUNT BATEMAN PAR Mr. MARTIN. ŒUVRE IER. Gravé par Melle. Laymon. Prix 6 tt. A PARIS Chez Mr. Le Clerc, rüe St. Honoré vis a vis l'Oratoire chez le Bonnetier. Mr. Le Clerc, Md. rüe du Roule à la Croix d'Or. Madame Boivin, Mde. rüe St. Honoré à la Regle d'Or. AVEC PRIVILEGE DU ROY., ca. 1744; M768; Three parts, quarto, 238x179 (246x184): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Letter of dedication, verso blank, [i-ii]. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO SECONDO. Bottom of first page of music of VIOLINO PRIMO SIGNED: "F. Martin". Bound with nos. 25, 136, 201, 202, and 235.
  Grave C| - Allegro C
  Trio sonatas, op. 1; Martin, François, 1727-1757; Boivin, Mme. (Elisabeth-Catherine Ballard), d. 1776; Croix d'Or; Le Clerc, Mr.; Le Clerc, Charles-Nicolas, 1697-1774; Le Clerc, Jean-Pantaléon, d. 1759; Règle d'Or; Laymon, Mademoiselle, fl. 1743-1752; Paris (France); Jig; Minuet; A; B♭; C; F; G; E; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Allegro; Andante; Giga allegro; Grave; Largo; Minuetto
  Appears in Le Clerc's catalogue of 1744 (Devriès, p. 222).
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SONATAS of three Parts, for two Violins & a Bass with a through Bass for ye Organ Harpsicord or arch Lute Compos'd by Michele Mascitti. Opera Quinta. LONDON, Printed for J. Walsh Servt. to her Majty. at ye Harp & Hoboy in Katherine Street in ye Strand, & J. Hare at ye Viol & Flute in Cornhill near ye Royal Exchang, ca. 1712; M1216; Four parts, folio, 274x173 (280x178): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-10. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. VIOLONCELLO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-9. Blank, [10]. Unfigured. ORGANO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO.
  Un Poco Andante 3/4
  Allegro e spicco C
  SONATA a Violino solo e Basso e secondo Violino se piace V D
  Allemanda spiritoso C
  Corrente Andante C 3/4
  Sarabanda C 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 1. Nos. 7-12; Trio sonatas, op. 5 (Walsh); Mascitti, Michele, 1663 or 1664-1760; Hare, John, d. 1725; Harp and Hoboy; Viol and Flute; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Hare, John, d. 1725; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Allemande; Corrente; Jig; Sarabande; A; C; D; E; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; C; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro e spicco; Allemanda allegro; Allemanda spiritoso; Corrente andante; Giga allegro; Grave; Largo; Sarabanda; Spiritoso; Un poco andante; Vivace
  Smith no. 434.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - VIOLONCELLO
  - ORGANO
- SIX SONATAS FOR TWO VIOLINS AND A BASS, COMPOSED BY Sig. BARTOLOMEO MENESINI. BY HIS MAJESTY'S ROYAL LETTERS PATENT. LONDON: PRINTED AND SOLD BY HENRY FOUGHT, AT THE LYRE AND OWL, IN ST. MARTIN'S-LANE, NEAR LONG-ACRE. [Price Two SHILLINGS and SIX-PENCE.], 1767; M2244; Three parts, folio, 267x180 (Letter- press): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank, [1-2]. Half-title "TRII di MENESINI. VIOLINO PRIMO.", p. [3]. Music, pp. 4-9. "NEW MUSIC, Printed and Sold by HENRY FOUGT, MUSICAL TYPOGRAPHER...", p. [10]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank, [1-2]. Half-title "TRII di MENESINI. VIOLINO SECONDO.", p. [3]. Music, pp. 4-9. Blank, [10]. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO SECONDO, with "BASSO" substituted for "VIOLINO SECONDO" on half-title.
  Tempo di minue 3/4
  Tempo di minue 3/8
  Trio sonatas; Menesini, Bartolomeo; Fougt, Henric, 1720-1782; Lyre and Owl; Fougt, Henric, 1720-1782; London (England); Minuet; A; C; E; E♭; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; Allegretto; Allegro; Andante; Largo; Tempo di minuet
  The entire work is set in movable type. The title-page of VIOLINO PRIMO has several MS additions, all in the same hand.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS FOR TWO VIOLINS with a Thorough Bass for the Harpsicord or Violoncello. COMPOS'D BY ANGELO MORIGI da Rimini. London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catharine Street in the Strand. Of whom may be had For 2 Violins and a Bass. [list of works beginning with: "Solniz 12 Sonatas" and ending with "Birkenstock's Solos"], 1751; M3664; Three parts, folio, 243x178 (254x188): PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. SECONDO: Same as PRIMO. BASSO: Same as PRIMO.
  Trio sonatas. Selections; Morigi, Angelo, 1725-1801; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); B♭; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Andante; Larghetto; Largo
  Smith-Humphries, no. 1120.
  London Daily Advertiser
  , October 12, 1751.
  - PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- DUET, for Two PERFORMERS on One Grand Piano Forte, Composed by W.A. MOZART. Op. XIV. Entd at Statrs Hall. Price s4. LONDON. Printed for Monzani & Cimador, Music Sellers, to His Royal Highness the Prince of Wales No. 2 Pall Mall., Between 1800 and 1803; Deest.; Score, quarto, 248x176 (276x206): Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-31. Blank, [32]. Odd-numbered pages have heading "PRIMO", even-numbered pages "SECONDO".
  SONATA C
  Sonata, piano, 4 hands, K.521; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Monzani & Cimador; Monzani & Cimador; London (England); C; 2/4; 3/4; Allegretto; Andante; [no indication]
  Publisher at this address during this period (Humphries-Smith, p. 236).
  - Score, quarto, 248x176 (276x206)
- Six SONATAS For two GERMAN FLUTES or two VIOLINS And a BASS Composed by Sigr: P: NARDINI. London. Price s7h.6d. Printed and Sold by R. BREMNER at the Harp and Hautboy Facing Somerset House in the STRAND., ca. 1770; N42 (Sonata VI: G major); Three parts, quarto, 230x177 (253x190): PRIMO: Title, verso blank. "A CATALOGUE of Vocal and Instrumental Music. Printed by R: Bremner, at the Harp and Hautboy facing Somerset-house in the Strand, LONDON.", p. [1]. Music, pp. 2-14. SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-14. BASSO: Same as SECONDO.
  Trio sonatas. Selections; Nardini, Pietro, 1722-1793; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; Harp and Hautboy; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; London (England); B♭; C; D; F; G; E; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; Adagio ma non troppo; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Andante
  - PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- Six SONATAS FOR TWO VIOLINS and a BASS Composed by SIGR: GIO: BATTISTA NOFERI Opera VIIma. LONDON. Printed by R: BREMNER, at the Harp and Hautboy, Opposite Somerset-House in the STRAND., ca. 1763; N749; Three parts, folio, 240x179 (265x188): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO.
  SONATA I E♭
  Allegro Non Tropo C|
  Tempi di Minuet 3/4
  Allegro non Tropo C|
  Tempo di Minuet 3/8
  Trio sonatas, op. 7; Noferi, Giovan Battista, 18 th cent.; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; Harp and Hautboy; London (England); Minuet; A; C; E♭; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro non tropo; Andante; Largo; Tempi di minuet; Tempo di minuet
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SEI TRII, a due Violini e Basso, Composti da Gio Battista Noferi, e da esso dedicati a Sua Eccellenza LADY BRIDGET LANE OPERA IX [line] LONDON Printed by WELCKER in Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho Where may be had by the same Author [list of works beginning with: "Six Duets for 2 German Flutes and Six Duets for 2 Guittars." and ending with: "by Sigr. Zappa two Setts of Sonatas for 2 Violins and a Bass &c. &c. &c."], ca. 1770; N752; Three parts, folio, 239x182 (263x188): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. "A CATALOGUE of Vocal and Instrumental Musick Printed for and Sold by PETER WELCKER at his Musick Shop in Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho LONDON.", p. [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO SECONDO.
  Minue Andte. 3/4
  TRIO IV E
  Allegro non troppo C|
  Minue Affetto. 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 9; Noferi, Giovan Battista, 18 th cent.; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; London (England); Minuet; B♭; C; D; E; E♭; G; 3/4; C|; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Allegro non troppo; Minue affettuoso; Minue andante; Tempo di menuetto; Tempo di minuet; [no indication]
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS for two Violins with a Thorough Bass for the Harpsichord Humbly Dedicated To the Right Honble. Lady Bingley Composed by Battista Noferi OPERA 10th. LONDON Printed by WELCKER in Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho Where may be had by the same Author [list of works beginning with: "Six Trios Op: 9." and ending with: "a fourth sett of Lessons by Vento &c. &c. &c. &c."], ca. 1770; N754; Three parts, quarto, 246x201 (269x204): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. "A CATALOGUE of Vocal and Instrumental MUSICK Printed for and Sold by PETER WELCKER at his Musick Shop in Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho LONDON.", p. [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-9. Blank, [10].
  Allo. maestoso C
  Tempo di Minue 3/4
  Allegro maestoso C|
  Tempo Giusto 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 10; Noferi, Giovan Battista, 18 th cent.; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; London (England); Minuet; A; C; D; E♭; F; G; 3/4; C|; Allegro; Allegro maestoso; Allegro non troppo; Allegretto maestoso; Andante; Andantino; Tempo giusto; Tempo di minue; Tempo di minuè
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- Six Sonatas FOR Two Violins Violoncello or HARPSICORD. Most humbly dedicated To the Lady Augusta BY HER ROYAL HIGHNESS' most devoted and Dutiful Servant Fred: Nussen Opera 2da. London Printed for the Author by John Walsh Musick Printer & Instrument Maker to his Majesty, in Catherine Street, Strand., 1753 or 1754; N815; Three parts, folio, 241x177 (255x182): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. Label at top of title-page of VIOLINO PRIMO: "Sold at Welcker's Musick Shop Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho".
  Tempo di Minuet Andante 3/4
  March Largo C
  Gratiosa 3/4
  Allegro moderato [C]
  Trio sonatas, op. 2; Nussen, Frederick; Welcker's Musick Shop; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Gavotte; March; Minuet; Siciliana; A; D; E♭; F; G; 3/2; 3/4; 6/8; C; C|; Adagio; Affettuoso; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Con spirito; Gavotta; Grazioso; Largo; March largo; Siciliana; Tempo di minuet andante; Tempo giusto; Vivace
  Smith-Humphries, no. 1137.
  Whitehall Evening-Post
  , December 29, 1753-January 1, 1754.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATES En Trio Pour une Flûte, Violon, et Basse. DEDIÉES À Mr. DE MARANS LE FILS. Par Mr. PAGANELLI Compositeur des Opera Italiens de S. A. S. Monseigneur le Duc Regnant de Brunswick Lunebourg. ŒUVRE PREMIER. Gravé par L. Hüe Prix 6tt. A PARIS Chez Mr. le Clerc le cadet rue St. Honoré près l'Oratoire Le Sr. le Clerc Md. rue du Roule à la Croix d'Or. Madame Boivin Mde. rue St. Honoré à ls Regle d'Or. AVEC PRIVILEGE DU ROI., ca. 1741-1742; P56; Three parts, quarto, 235x170 (246x180): Flauto: Title, verso blank. Letter of dedication, verso blank. [i-ii]. Catalogue [see Notes, below], p. [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Violino: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Basso: Same as Violino. Bound with nos. 25, 136, 190, 202, and 235.
  Andantino C|
  Staccatto C - A Cappella C|
  Rondeau Larghetto, et Gratioso C|
  Mezzo Adagio 2/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 1; Paganelli, Giuseppe Antonio, 1710-ca. 1763; Boivin, Mme. (Elisabeth-Catherine Ballard), d. 1776; Croix d'Or; Le Clerc, Mr., le Cadet.; Le Clerc, Sr., Mr.; Le Clerc, Charles-Nicolas, 1697-1774; Le Clerc, Jean-Pantaléon, d. 1759; Règle d'Or; Hüe, L.; Paris (France); Minuet; Rondo; A; C; D; G; E; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; A cappella; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro con spirito; Andante moderato; Andantino; Cantabile; Mezzo adagio; Minuet; Presto; Rondeau larghetto et grazioso; Staccatto
  Appears in Le Clerc's catalogue of the same date (Devriès, p. 235) and issued with catalogue of the same date (see Notes, below).
  The catalogue is not listed in Devriès but falls between Le Clerc's catalogue no. 2 (issued December 1740) and no. 3 (issued between 1741 and September 1742).
  - Flauto
  - Violino
  - Basso
- SIX SONATES De Chambre, POUR DEUX VIOLONS, OU FLÛTES AVEC LA BASSE. DEDIÉ A Mr. Alexandre Vollrath BARON D'EICKSTEDT LE FILS, Seigneur de Rothen, Clempenow, Et Brystow. PAR Mr. PAGANELLI Compositeur des Operas Italiens DE S.A.S.Mgneur. LE DUC REGNANT DE BRUNSWICK LUNEBOURG. ŒVRE 7e. Chez Mr. Le Clerc rue St. honoré vis a vis L'Oratoire chez le Bonnetier au Second, Et aux adresses ordinaires. Prix 6tt. Avec Privilege du Roi., ca. 1744; P57; Three parts, quarto, 226X178 (236X179): Primo: Title, verso blank. Catalogue [see Notes, below], p. [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Secondo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Basso: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-9. Blank, [10]. Bound with nos. 25, 136, 190, 201, and 236.
  TRATTENIMENTO I G
  TRATTENIMENTO II C
  Con Spirto 3/4
  TRATTENIMENTO III A
  Larghesto C
  Brillante 3/8
  TRATTENIMENTO IV e
  Presto 3/4 [recte:2/4]
  TRATTENIMENTO V D
  a Capella C
  Moderato 3/4 [recte: 2/4]
  Con Spirito 3/8
  TRATTENIMENTO VI E
  Aria Cantabile 3/8
  Presto 3/4 [recte: 2/4]
  Trio sonatas, op. 7; Paganelli, Giuseppe Antonio, 1710-ca. 1763; Le Clerc, Mr.; Le Clerc, Charles-Nicolas, 1697-1774; Paris (France); Aria; Minuet; A; C; D; E; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; Allegro; Andante; Andantino; Aria cantabile; Brillante; Con spirito; Grazioso; Larghetto; Moderato; Presto; Tempo di minuet; A capella
  Appears in Le Clerc's catalogue of 1744 (Devriès, p. 235).
  The catalogue is not listed in Devriès but falls between Le Clerc's catalogue no. 4 (issued August 1743) and no. 5 (issued 1744).
  - Primo
  - Secondo
  - Basso
- SIX SONATAS for two VIOLINS, with a TENOR and THOROUGH BASS for the HARPSICHORD or VIOLONCELLO Composed by Sigr. Nicolo Pasquali 1st. Set LONDON Printed for John Johnson at the Harp & Crown in Cheapside of whom may be had [list of works beginning with: "Avison's 6 Sonatas." and ending with: "Campioni's Sonatas."], ca. 1750; P988; Incomplete set, viola part wanting: Three parts, folio, 252x175 (264x185): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-10.
  Spiccato C
  Moderato e Grazioso 3/4
  Sonatas, violins (2), viola, continuo. 1st set; Pasquali, Nicolo, ca. 1718-1757; Harp and Crown; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; London (England); Jig; Minuet; B♭; D; E; G; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro assai; Andante; Andantino; Giga allegro; Largo e puntato; Minuet; Moderato e grazioso; Presto; Spiccato
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- Eight DUETTS for a VIOLIN and VIOLONCELLO, or Two Violoncellos; Humbly Dedicated to His Grace The DUKE of MARLBOROUGH: Composed by Stephen Paxton Opera Seconda. To which is added The Highland Laddie, a Scots Air, with Variations for a Violoncello and a Violin. To be had of the Author No. 72 Great Titchfield Street, near Cavendish Square., ca. 1780; P1074; Score, quarto, 276x194 (280x205): Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-43. Lower right corner of title-page has in MS: "10/6"; in lower left corner of first page of music: "Baker Sculpt."; lower right corner of same page signed: "S: Paxton".
  DUETTO I F
  Andantino Grazioso 2/4
  DUETTO III A
  Largo e Sostenuto C|
  DUETTO V c
  Allegro Con Spirito C|
  Grazioso. Rondeau 3/4
  Un poco Vivace 2/4
  Pastorale Larghetto 6/8
  Andantino Grazioso. - Aria con Variationi 2/4
  DUETTO VII D
  Rondeau Tempo di Minuetto 3/4
  DUETTO VIII G
  Resoluto 2/4
  The Highland Laddie, a Scots Air, with Variations for a Violoncello D
  Andte C|
  The Highland Laddie, a Scots Air, with Variations for a Violin A
  Duets, violin, violoncello, op. 2; Highland laddie, The; Paxton, Stephen, 1734-1787; Baker; London (England); Aria; Minuet; Rondo; Variations; A; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegretto; Allegro; Allegro con spirito; Andante; Andantino grazioso; Andantino grazioso; Aria con variazioni; Grazioso; Grazioso. Rondeau; Larghetto; Largo e sostenuto; Pastorale larghetto; Resoluto; Rondeau allegretto; Rondeau tempo di minuetto; Un poco vivace; Vivace
- SEI TRIETTI A DUE VIOLINI e Basso DEDICATI A Monsieur Ferrand Fermiere Générale DA FERDINANDO PELLEGRINO Napolitano OPERA PRIMA Gravé par Melle. Bertin. Prix 6tt. A PARIS Aux adresses ordinaires. A LYON Chez Mr. de Brotonne, Md. ruë Merciere. AVEC PRIVILEGE DU ROY., ca. 1753; P1154; Three parts, quarto, 234x177 (242x185): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Letter of dedication, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Violino Secondo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Basso: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-10.
  Allegro non troppo 2/4
  Andante Spiritoso 3/8
  Andante spiritoso 2/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 1; Pellegrino, Ferdinando, ca. 1715-ca. 1766; De Brotonne, Étienne, ca. 1707-1757; Bertin, Mlle., fl. 1740-1763; Paris (France); Lyon (France); Minuet; B♭; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro non troppo; Andante; Andante spiritoso; Minuetto; Presto
  Michel Brenet ("La librairie musicale en France de 1653 à 1790, d'après les Registres de privileges," Sammelbände der Internationalen Musikgesellschaft, 8 [1906-1907], p. 448), cites Royal Privilege of December 11, 1753, to Pellegrino for "des trio et autres pièces de musique instrumental". BUCEM dates this as ca. 1765, but Brotonne was not at this address after 1757 (Devriès-Lesure, v.1, p. 162).
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Basso
- Six SONATES a deux VIOLONS et BASSE, Dediées A Son Altese Serenissime Monseigneur le Duc Ferdinand, DUC de BRONSVIC et Lunebourg etc. etc. Composées par C. A. PESCH. Oeuvre III. LONDON Printed for & sold by William Napier in the Strand Price 7s. 6d, 1775; P1526 ("à deux violons"); Three parts, quarto, 265x187 (272x207): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp 2-14. VIOLINO SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-10. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-9. Blank, [10].
  Minuetto un poco andante 3/4
  Amoroso 3/8
  Trio sonatas, op. 3; Pesch, Carl August; Napier, William, 1740?-1812; Napier, William, 1740?-1812; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; A; B♭; C; D; E♭; F; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; C|; Allegretto; Allegretto moderato; Amoroso; Andante; Andantino; Grazioso; Minuetto un poco andante; Rondo; Rondo presto; Tempo di minuetto
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- DOUZES CAPRICES A VIOLON SEUL Composées & Dediées A. S. E. Mr. D. ALBERTO LITTA Conseiller Intime de S. M. J. &c. &c. &c. Par WENCESLAS PICHL Directeur de Musique de S. A. R. Monseigneur L'Archiduc Ferdinand d'Autriche Oeuvre XIX. Cheéz J. J. HUMMEL à Berlin avec Privilége du Roi à Amsterdam au Gand Magazin de Musique et aux Adresses Ordinaires. No. 944. Prix f2-:-:, 1796; P2296; Score, quarto, 133x182 (138x197): Title, verso blank, [1-2]. Blank, [3]. Music, pp. 4-27. Blank, [28].
  CAPRICE I C
  CAPRICE II c
  CAPRICE III G
  Allegro Con Brio 2/4
  CAPRICE IV g
  CAPRICE V D
  CAPRICE VI d
  Larghetto C - Allegro Moderato C
  CAPRICE VII A
  CAPRICE VIII a
  CAPRICE IX F
  CAPRICE X f
  CAPRICE XI E♭
  CAPRICE XII eb
  Caprices, violin, op. 19; Pichl, Wenzel, 1741-1805; Grand magazine de musique; Hummel, Johann Julius, 1728-1798; Berlin (Germany); Amsterdam (Netherlands); A; C; D; E♭; F; G; Eb; 2/4; 3/4; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro con brio; Allegro moderato; Andante; Andante moderato; Andantino; Larghetto; Vivace
  Berlinische Nachrichten von Staats- und gelehrten Sachen
  , March 5, 1796.
  Plate no. 944 throughout.
- Six NOTTURNOS OR Night Pieces for two VIOLINS or two German Flutes AND A BASS Composed by Signr: Francesco Piombanti Price 3s. London Printed for Henry Thorowgood No. 6 North Piazza Royal Exchange. Where may be had For two Violins and Bass [list of works beginning with: "Galleoti's 2 Sonatas" and ending with: "Stocking Cantata"], ca. 1765; P2422; Three parts, quarto, 290x183 (300x191): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-6. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO.
  Largo C - Allegro 2/4
  Notturnos, violins (2), continuo; Piombanti, Francesco; Thorowgood, Henry; London (England); Minuet; B♭; C; E♭; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; Allegro; Andante; Largo; Minuet
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- A Second Sett of Six SONATAS for the Piano Forte or Harpsichord with an Accompaniment for a VIOLIN humbly dedicated to the Right Honble: LADY CHAMPNEYS and Composed by SIGR: PIOZZI Opera III. Price 10:6 LONDON Printed and Sold by JOHN WELCKER (Music Seller to their MAJESTIES and all the ROYAL FAMILY) No. 10 Hay Market. Where may be had by the above Author. 6 Quartets for Piano Forte with Accompts. Op: 1ma. Pr: 10=6 Six Lessons for Piano Forte &c. with Violin Accompt. Op: 2. Pr: 10=6 &c., ca. 1779; P2429 (Sonata V: E♭Major).; Score, quarto, 265x201 (276x203): Title, verso blank. "A Catalogue of Vocal & Instrumental Music Engrav'd Printed and Sold Wholesale Retail and for Exportation. by JOHN WELCKER Music Seller to their MAJESTIES & all the ROYAL FAMILY Removed from Gerrard Street Soho to No. 10 Hay Market LONDON.", pp. 1-4. Music, pp. 1-51. Blank, [52].
  Allegro maestoso 2/4
  Allo. con Spirito 2/4
  Andante maestoso 2/4
  Rondo 2/4 (C major)
  Non tanto Allegro 2/4
  Sonatas, violin, piano, op. 3; Piozzi, Gabriele Mario, 1740-1809; Welcker, John; Welcker, John; Welcker, John; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; B♭; C; D; E♭; F; 2/4; 3/4; Allegro; Allegro spiritoso; Allegro maestoso; Allegro con spirito; Andante maestoso; Andantino; Minuetto; Non tanto allegro; Rondo
  Ronald Kidd, "Piozzi, Gabriele Mario," The New Grove, v. 14, p. 761.
  The latest items listed in the catalogue are from 1779 or possibly 1780.